A Finding Aid to the Focus Gallery Records, 1963-1987, in the Archives of American Art AAA.focugall
Archives of American Art
- Exhibition files, 1966-1985; Series 3; 8.5 Linear feet Box 2-10
  - Group Exhibiton files, 1966-1985; Subseries 3.2; 3.6 Linear feet Boxes 7-10
    - "Four French Photographers" (1977), 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - "Four Young Photographers" (1970) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - "The Glow of Ages" (1972), 1971-1973 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "Golden Gate Park" (1976), 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "Hand Colored Photographs" (1981) (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - "Hawaiian Viewpoints" (1980), 1979-1980 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Image Circle Photographers" (1971), 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "Images of Concern" (1972), 1971-1975 (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
    - "Inside Czechoslovakia as Viewed by Sixteen European Photographers" (1967) (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - "Italian Architecture, 19th Century" (1985) (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - "Japanese Photography" (1975), 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "Kaiser Exhibition I" (1970) (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - "Kaiser Exhibition II" (1978) (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - "A Kind of Beatness" (1975), 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - "Luminous Discoveries" (1967), 1966-1967 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - "Master Photographers: A Sentimental Celebration" (1981) (Box 8, Folder 28-30)
    - "Meniscus in Focus: 15 Photographers" (1985) (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - "The Mother Lode: Then and Now" (1979), 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
    - "Nature Photographs" (1971) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "A New Concept in Collecting" (1985), 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "Night Photography" (1984), 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
    - "The Open Door" (1968), 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Oriental Eye" (1973), 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 8-9)
    - "Polaroid Photography" (1973), 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - "Photographs by the Westons Edward and Cole" (1972), 1971-1972 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - "Photography for the Art in the Embassies Program" (1967) (Box 9, Folder 12-15)
    - "Photography from Czechoslovakia" (1973), 1973-1974 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - "Photography from Nepal" (1984) (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - "Photographic Portfolios" (1975), 1971-1975 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - "Portraits" (1979), 1977-1979 (Box 9, Folder 19-21)
    - "Portraits of John W. Winkler" (1979) (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - "Print Exhibition and Sale" (1970), 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - "Professors of Photography" (1967), 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - "The 1906 Quake and Fire" (1971) (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - "Tony Ray-Jones and Keith Collie" (1979), 1978-1979 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - "Rolling Renaissance" (1968), 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - "Photography by Group 233.03" (1967) (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - "San Francisco Women Artists Present an Exhibition of Photographs at Focus Gallery" (1968) (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - "San Francisco Women Artists' Fourth Annual Photography Show" (1971), 1970-1971 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - "San Francisco Women Artitsts' 50th Anniversary Photography Show" (1975), 1970-1975 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - "Seven Photographers from New Mexico" (1969), 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - "Sisters" (1973), 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - "The Snapshot: Then and Now" (1976), 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - "Studio 74" (1974) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Ten Photographers from Sweden" (1969) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - "Tenth Anniversary Exhibition" (1976) (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
    - "Three Canadian Photographers" (1979) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - "Three Japanese Visions" (1982), 1981-1982 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "Three Photographers and the Abstract" (1970), 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "Three Photographers and the Place" (1970), 1969-1970 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - "Three Photojournalists" (1983), 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - "Three Views of India" (1978), 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 10-11)
    - "Through a Doctor's Eyes" (1985) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "To a Cabin and Other Photographs" (1974), 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "Trends in Color" (1983), 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 14-15)
    - "The Turbulent Sixties in the Bay Area: Protest Photography" (1984), 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 16-18)
    - "Two Photographers from Paris" (1976), 1976-1983 (Box 10, Folder 19-20)
    - "Two Views of Mallorca, Spain" (1985), 1984 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - "A Variety Show" (1971), 1971-1975 (Box 10, Folder 22-23)
    - "Visual Dialogue Foundations Founders' Portfolio" (1970) (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - "Visual Studies Workshop Gallery", 1976, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - "The Westons: Three Generations" (1985), 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 26-27)
    - "Where There's Smoke, San Francisco Earthquake and Fire Seventy-Fifth Anniversary" (1981), 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Artists files, 1966-1978; Series 4; 8 Folders Boxes 10-11
  Folders are arranged alphabetically
  Artists files contain collected materials about photographers of interest who did not exhibit at the Gallery. Files contain primarily printed materials, but there are also biographical materials, correspondence, and some sample photographs.
  - Artists Files A-B, 1966-1985 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Artists Files C-D, 1966-1985 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Artists Files E-G, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Artists Files H-K, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Artists Files L-M, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Artists Files N-Q, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Artists Files R-Si, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Artists Files Sm-Sz, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Artists Files T-Z, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Financial and Legal files, 1966-1987; Series 5; 6 Folders Box 11
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  Contain bookshop, general accounting and insurance records, general business invoices and receipts, leases, and tax documents.
  - Accounting Records, 1967-1985 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Bookshop, 1968-1985 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Insurance, various, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Invoices and Checks, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Rental Leases and Correspondence, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Tax Papers, 1966-1983 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Sales and Inventories, 1966-1987; Series 6; 11 Folders Box 11
  This series includes customer index cards, inventories and price lists of both prints and books, and receipts for photographs bought, sold, and on consignment.
  - Bookshop, 1981, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Customer Files, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 15-16)
  - Customer Files by Artist Name, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Iventory, Other Items, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Print Inventory, 1981-1982 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - General Pricing Information Correspondence, 1976-1985 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - General Pricing Information, undated (Box 11, Folder 21-22)
  - Receipts for Photographs, 1966-1985 (Box 11, Folder 23-24)
- Printed Materials, 1966-1987; Series 7; 7 Folders Box 11 and Hol 12
  Folders are arranged alphabetically, then chronologically
  Contains news clippings, press releases of Focus Gallery and other galleries, and Focus Gallery’s bookshop catalogs.
  - Bookshop Catalogs, 1966-1987 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - General Interest, 1966-1968 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - General Interest, 1969-1977 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - General Interest, 1978-1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Press Releases, Focus Gallery, 1967-1985 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Press Releases, Other Galleries, circa 1960-circa 1970
  - Press Releases, Other Galleries, circa 1982-1984 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Guest Books, 1978-1985; 1966-1970; Series 8; 6 Folders Hol 12-13
  These bound volumes and loose pages contain names, addresses, and sometimes comments, of visitors to Focus Gallery.
  - Guest Book, 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Guest Book, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Guest Books, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Guest Books, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Guest Books, 1978-1981 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Guest Books, 1981-1985 (Box 13, Folder 4)